export const quiz = {
    questions: [
      {
        id: 1,
        question: 'Which of these is a vine training system named for a 19th-century French agronomist, in which a vine’s oldest branches and most of its younger branches are cut in winter, leaving just one or two young branches (aka canes) for bud growth?',
        answers: ['Cordon', 'Geuillot', 'Guyot', 'Gillot'],
        correctAnswer: 'Guyot',
      },
      {
        id: 2,
        question: 'Beyond the Champagne region, winemakers throughout France use the Champagne method (aka méthode traditionnelle) to produce sparkling wines under this name:',
        answers: ['Crémant', 'Riversaltes', 'Barsac', 'Vermouth'],
        correctAnswer: 'Crémant',
      },
      {
        id: 3,
        question: 'Generally speaking, what are the ideal conditions for growing Sangiovese vines?',
        answers: [
          'Marl and sandstone soils with dry weather', 
          'Very rocky soils and damp, rainy weather', 
          'Marl soils and a very cool climate', 
          'Pebbly soils and extremely hot, sunny summers'
        ],
        correctAnswer: 'Marl and sandstone soils with dry weather',
      },
      {
        id: 4,
        question: 'In 1855, the estates of Bordeaux’s Left Bank were classified in a tiered system by the command of this French leader:',
        answers: ['Louis XVI', 'Napoleon III', 'Charles IX', 'Charles de Gaulle'],
        correctAnswer: 'Napoleon III',
      },
      {
        id: 5,
        question: 'If a wine is showing sweet-sour vinegary aromas and flavors, it might contain too much of this chemical compound also found in, you guessed it, vinegar:',
        answers: ['Resveratrol', 'Lactic acid', 'Acetic acid', 'Capsaicin'],
        correctAnswer: 'Acetic acid',
      },
      {
        id: 6,
        question: 'In which of these island regions is Pinot Noir the second-most widely planted wine grape variety after Sauvignon Blanc?',
        answers: ['Corsica', 'Canary Islands', 'Sardinia', 'New Zealand'],
        correctAnswer: 'New Zealand',
      },
      {
        id: 7,
        question: 'With one of the world’s largest collections of Napa Valley Cabernets, famed restaurant Press is an endeavor from the family behind which of these well-known wineries?',
        answers: ['Harlan', 'Heitz', 'Rudd', 'Mayacamas'],
        correctAnswer: 'Rudd',
      },
      {
        id: 8,
        question: 'Starting in the 1980s, Aurelio Montes—the “dean of Chilean winemakers”—started a viticultural shift in Chile’s Apalta Valley by:',
        answers: [
          'Planting vines on hillsides, when most Chilean vineyards were on the valley floor', 
          'Using oak barrels for aging, something previously unheard of in Chile', 
          'Blending Cabernet Sauvignon with Malbec and Chardonnay', 
          'Producing Chile’s first sparkling wine'],
        correctAnswer: 'Planting vines on hillsides, when most Chilean vineyards were on the valley floor',
      },
      {
        id: 9,
        question: 'In the wider world of botany, which of these terms describes the study of identifying and classifying grapevines—an immensely important subject in the wine world?',
        answers: ['Vitisology', 'Labruscology', 'Ampelography', 'Agronomy'],
        correctAnswer: 'Ampelography',
      },
      {
        id: 10,
        question: 'This clay, egg-shaped vessel is used for making and aging wine in Georgia, one of the oldest-known winemaking regions in the world:',
        answers: ['Khantsi', 'Krater', 'Lagare', 'Qvevri'],
        correctAnswer: 'Qvevri',
      },
      {
        id: 11,
        question: 'Up to how many approved grape varieties can winemakers use to make the celebrated Châteauneuf-du-Pape reds of France’s Southern Rhône Valley?',
        answers: ['3', '8', '13', '93'],
        correctAnswer: '13',
      },
    ],
  };
  